Tyler Wenzel

≥ tylerwenzel9@gmail.com **⊘** tylerwenzel.dev **in** tylerwenzel **○** tylerwenzel

ABOUT ME

I am a full-stack software engineer with a passion for problem-solving and creating. I have experience working in JavaScript and Go, but am always excited when I can learn new tech. In my free time, I like to read, run (typically, not at the same time), and hopelessly root on my Cleveland Browns.

EXPERIENCE

Co-Creator/Software Engineer, *DataLoaf ⊘*

2024 - present

DataLoaf is an open-source self-hosted product analytics that allows for data ingestion and visualization.

- Built command line interface tool for DataLoaf infrastructure simplifying provisioning down to 4 steps using Go.
- Automated provisioning and teardown of 30+ resource AWS cloud infrastructure via Terraform.
- Designed and implemented data pipeline to ingest and store up to 500,000 events per second utilizing AWS API Gateway, Amazon Kinesis Data Streams, Amazon Data Firehose, and Amazon Redshift.
- Created data visualization application hosted on Amazon EC2 instance deployed through Docker containers.
- Implemented server-side Node.js SDK to collect 3 different types of data (user, event, update) from client application to send to data ingestion pipeline.
- Authored a comprehensive case study discussing Dataloaf's problem domain, system design, and key engineering decisions. This case study is available at data-loaf.com *∂*

Full Stack Web Developer, Open Source Projects

2022 - present

Independently developed open source applications including:

- *endpntr* A webhook reciever service to collect and inspect HTTP traffic sent to a generated enpoint. (Node, Express, Tailwind CSS, MongoDB, REST API, Digital Ocean, Nginx)
- Connector An interactive contact manager. (Node. js, Handlebars. js, and an Express API)

Financial Analyst, *Johnson and Johnson*

2020 - 2022

- Executed quarterly close responsibilities including capital expenditures, budget and sales forecasting
- Adhered to all accounting policies and standards to ensure company follows all compliance measures
- Supported Ethicon operating company providing budget and sales analysis to business partners
- Led expansion of tableau dashboard utilized across entire Medical Device segment

SKILLS

Frameworks

Express, Node.js, React, REST API

Databases

PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Amazon Redshift

Cloud

Amazon Redshift, Amazon Data Firehose, Amazon EC2, AWS API Gateway, AWS Lambda, Elastic Load Balancer

Languages

JavaScript, Go, HTML, CSS, Terraform

EDUCATION

Launch School 2022 – 2024

• A multi-year mastery-based curriculum teaching full-stack engineering fundamentals from first principles

Ohio State University, BSBA Finance

2016 - 2020

Employed as accounting TA for managerial and financial accounting from 2018-2020